<?xml version="1.0" ?> 
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
<channel>
<title>EurekAlert! - Technology, Engineering and Computer Science</title>
<description>The premier online source for science news since 1996. A service of the American Association for the Advancement of Science.</description>
<atom:link href="http://www.eurekalert.org/rss/technology_engineering.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<link>http://www.eurekalert.org</link>
<language>en-us</language> 
<copyright>Copyright 2016 American Association for the Advancement of Science (AAAS); All rights reserved.</copyright>  
<lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2016 05:48:00 EDT</lastBuildDate> 
<generator>EurekAlert!</generator>
<image>
  <title>EurekAlert! - Technology, Engineering and Computer Science</title> 
  <url>http://www.eurekalert.org/images/logo.gif</url> 
  <link>http://www.eurekalert.org</link> 
  <description>The premier online source for science news since 1996. A service of the American Association for the Advancement of Science.</description> 
</image>
<ttl>60</ttl> 
<webMaster>webmaster@eurekalert.org (EurekAlert!)</webMaster> 
<item>
	<title>Discovery of new ovarian cancer signaling hub points to target for limiting metastasis</title>
	<description>(&lt;i&gt;Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory&lt;/i&gt;) Researchers at CSHL have found a previously undiscovered pathway through which ovarian cells can be transformed into cancer cells, one they think provides an excellent opportunity for targeting by new drugs, which, when combined with others now in development, may be able to stave off metastatic disease.</description>
	<link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-07/cshl-don070616.php</link>
	<pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2016 00:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
	<guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-07/cshl-don070616.php</guid>
	
	
</item>
<item>
	<title>Four NYC medical centers receive new NIH precision medicine grant</title>
	<description>(&lt;i&gt;Columbia University Medical Center&lt;/i&gt;) Columbia University Medical Center and Weill Cornell Medicine, in collaboration with NewYork-Presbyterian and NYC Health + Hospitals/Harlem, have been awarded a grant from the NIH for up to $46.5 million over five years to enroll participants in the Cohort Program of President Barack Obama's Precision Medicine Initiative.</description>
	<link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-07/cumc-fnm070816.php</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 00:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
	<guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-07/cumc-fnm070816.php</guid>
	
	
</item>
<item>
	<title>CuRE pursues development of new dental adhesive with STTR grant</title>
	<description>(&lt;i&gt;Medical University of South Carolina&lt;/i&gt;) A new dental adhesive, which incorporates particles of copper iodide that curtail infections, could extend long-term bond strength when compared to typical adhesives and also reduce secondary caries.</description>
	<link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-07/muos-cpd070816.php</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 00:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
	<guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-07/muos-cpd070816.php</guid>
	
	
</item>
<item>
	<title>NASA looks at Typhoon Nepartak over Taiwan in visible and infrared light</title>
	<description>(&lt;i&gt;NASA/Goddard Space Flight Center&lt;/i&gt;) NASA's Aqua and Terra satellites provided a visible and infrared view of Typhoon Nepartak before and during its movement over Taiwan.</description>
	<link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-07/nsfc-nla070816.php</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 00:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
	<guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-07/nsfc-nla070816.php</guid>
	
	
</item>
<item>
	<title>Early daylight satellite image shows depression intensify into Tropical Storm Celia</title>
	<description>(&lt;i&gt;NASA/Goddard Space Flight Center&lt;/i&gt;) Tropical Depression 4E strengthened into a tropical storm as NOAA's GOES-West satellite captured an early daylight image of the storm.</description>
	<link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-07/nsfc-eds070816.php</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 00:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
	<guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-07/nsfc-eds070816.php</guid>
	
	
</item>
<item>
	<title>Recreating ancient vertebrate's first step on dry land</title>
	<description>(&lt;i&gt;National Science Foundation&lt;/i&gt;) Could a tail have allowed ancient vertebrates to make the transition from water to land?Reporting in Science today, researchers from Georgia Institute of Technology, Carnegie Mellon University, Clemson University and National Institute for Mathematical and Biological Synthesis described results of a groundbreaking study to answer this question using amphibious fish, a custom-built robot and mathematical models of movement.</description>
	<link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-07/nsf-rav070816.php</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 00:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
	<guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-07/nsf-rav070816.php</guid>
	
	
</item>
<item>
	<title>NASA sees Hurricane Blas closing its eye</title>
	<description>(&lt;i&gt;NASA/Goddard Space Flight Center&lt;/i&gt;) Hurricane Blas is weakening in the Eastern Pacific Ocean and when the Suomi NPP satellite passed overhead visible imagery showed that the eye of the storm had become filled with high clouds. Infrared imagery, however, still revealed a pinhole eye as the eye was becoming cloud-filled.</description>
	<link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-07/nsfc-nsh070816.php</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 00:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
	<guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-07/nsfc-nsh070816.php</guid>
	
	
</item>
<item>
	<title>Economics study finds volume discounts don't increase profitability for video game</title>
	<description>(&lt;i&gt;University of Chicago&lt;/i&gt;) A study by University of Chicago economists finds discounts tied to buying large quantities of virtual goods have little impact on profitability and do not increase the number of customers making purchases. The findings come from a field experiment of more than 14 million players of mobile games by King Digital Entertainment, maker of Candy Crush Saga.</description>
	<link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-07/uoc-esf070816.php</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 00:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
	<guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-07/uoc-esf070816.php</guid>
	
	
</item>
<item>
	<title>Extortion extinction</title>
	<description>(&lt;i&gt;University of Florida&lt;/i&gt;) Ransomware -- what hackers use to encrypt your computer files and demand money in exchange for freeing those contents -- is an exploding global problem with few solutions, but a team of University of Florida researchers says it has developed a way to stop it dead in its tracks.</description>
	<link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-07/uof-ee070816.php</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 00:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
	<guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-07/uof-ee070816.php</guid>
	
	
</item>
<item>
	<title>Setting the gold standard</title>
	<description>(&lt;i&gt;University of Florida&lt;/i&gt;) A team of University of Florida researchers has figured out how gold can be used in crystals grown by light to create nanoparticles, a discovery that has major implications for industry and cancer treatment and could improve the function of pharmaceuticals, medical equipment and solar panels.</description>
	<link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-07/uof-stg070816.php</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 00:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
	<guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-07/uof-stg070816.php</guid>
	
	
</item>
<item>
	<title>New record in microwave detection</title>
	<description>(&lt;i&gt;Aalto University&lt;/i&gt;) Aalto University scientists have broken the world record by fourteen fold in the energy resolution of thermal photodetection.</description>
	<link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-07/au-nri070816.php</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 00:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
	<guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-07/au-nri070816.php</guid>
	
	
</item>
<item>
	<title>After decades of clean up attempts, world's lakes still suffer from phosphorus pollution</title>
	<description>(&lt;i&gt;University of Southern Denmark&lt;/i&gt;) Leading scientists warn: Phosphorus pollution is a major concern. We need to speed up recovery treatments of lakes -- or accept poor freshwater quality. In a series of studies published in a special issue of the journal Water Research, leading scientists assess how to control phosphorus pollution in lakes.</description>
	<link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-07/uosd-ado070816.php</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 00:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
	<guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-07/uosd-ado070816.php</guid>
	
	
</item>
<item>
	<title>Atomic bits despite zero-point energy?</title>
	<description>(&lt;i&gt;Forschungszentrum Juelich&lt;/i&gt;) Scientists at J&#252;lich have found out that zero-point energy plays an important role in the stability of nanomagnets. These are of great technical interest for the magnetic storage of data, but so far have never been sufficiently stable. Researchers are now pointing the way to making it possible to produce nanomagnets with low zero-point energy and thus a higher degree of stability (Nanoletters).</description>
	<link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-07/fj-abd070816.php</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 00:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
	<guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-07/fj-abd070816.php</guid>
	
	
</item>
<item>
	<title>Learning from the mussel, scientists create a biologically active titanium surface</title>
	<description>(&lt;i&gt;RIKEN&lt;/i&gt;) Based on insights from mussels -- which are able to attach themselves very tightly to even metallic surfaces due to special proteins found in their byssal threads -- scientists from RIKEN have successfully attached a biologically active molecule to a titanium surface, paving the way for implants that can be more biologically beneficial.</description>
	<link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-07/r-lft070816.php</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 00:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
	<guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-07/r-lft070816.php</guid>
	
	
</item>
<item>
	<title>Physicists discover family of tetraquarks</title>
	<description>(&lt;i&gt;Syracuse University&lt;/i&gt;) Physicists in the College of Arts and Sciences have made science history by confirming the existence of a rare four-quark particle and discovering evidence of three other 'exotic' siblings.   Their findings are based on data from the Large Hadron Collider (LHC), the world's biggest, most powerful particle accelerator, located at the CERN science laboratory in Geneva, Switzerland.</description>
	<link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-07/su-pdf070716.php</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 00:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
	<guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-07/su-pdf070716.php</guid>
	
	
</item>
<item>
	<title>Researchers show phone calls can forecast dengue fever outbreaks</title>
	<description>(&lt;i&gt;New York University&lt;/i&gt;) A team of scientists has developed a system that can forecast the outbreak of dengue fever by simply analyzing the calling behavior of citizens to a public-health hotline. This telephone-based disease surveillance system can forecast two to three weeks ahead of time, and with intra-city granularity, the outbreak of dengue fever, a mosquito-borne virus that infects up to 400,000 people each year.</description>
	<link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-07/nyu-rsp070516.php</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 00:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
	<guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-07/nyu-rsp070516.php</guid>
	
	
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientists simulate tiny bacteria-powered 'windfarm'</title>
	<description>(&lt;i&gt;University of Oxford&lt;/i&gt;) A team of scientists from Oxford University has shown how the natural movement of bacteria could be harnessed to assemble and power microscopic 'windfarms' -- or other man-made micromachines such as smartphone components.</description>
	<link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-07/uoo-sst070516.php</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 00:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
	<guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-07/uoo-sst070516.php</guid>
	
	
</item>
<item>
	<title>2016 Young Investigator Award</title>
	<description>(&lt;i&gt;Institut national de la recherche scientifique - INRS&lt;/i&gt;) Professor Tiago H. Falk of INRS's Energie Mat&#233;riaux Telecommunications Research Centre has won the 2016 Young Investigator Award  presented by Sigma Xi in recognition of his research excellence in physical sciences and engineering. He is the first Canadian scientist to win this award.</description>
	<link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-07/indl-2yi070716.php</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2016 00:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
	<guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-07/indl-2yi070716.php</guid>
	
	
</item>
<item>
	<title>New Mexico African American Affairs office honors 2 from Sandia</title>
	<description>(&lt;i&gt;DOE/US Department of Energy&lt;/i&gt;) Two Sandia National Laboratories employees have been named recipients of 2016 Outstanding Service Awards from the New Mexico Office of African American Affairs (OAAA).Research engineer Conrad James and Theresa A. Carson, a senior manager in Sandia's Supply Chain Management Center, were recognized for their strong commitment to improving the quality of life for African Americans in the community. The 13th annual service awards recognize dedication to education, community development, health care advocacy and economic advancement for African Americans.</description>
	<link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-07/ddoe-nma070716.php</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2016 00:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
	<guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-07/ddoe-nma070716.php</guid>
	
	
</item>
<item>
	<title>NJIT receives $1M grant from Keck Foundation for pioneering research in biophysics and nanotechnology</title>
	<description>(&lt;i&gt;New Jersey Institute of Technology&lt;/i&gt;) New Jersey Institute of Technology (NJIT) has received a $1 million grant from the W.M. Keck Foundation for a three-year project titled 'Engineering New Materials Based on Topological Phonon Edge Modes.'</description>
	<link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-07/njio-nr070716.php</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2016 00:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
	<guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-07/njio-nr070716.php</guid>
	
	
</item>
<item>
	<title>Sensing trouble: A new way to detect hidden damage in bridges, roads</title>
	<description>(&lt;i&gt;University of Delaware&lt;/i&gt;) University of Delaware engineers Erik Thostenson and Thomas Schumacher have documented a new approach for monitoring the structural health of roads, bridges and other structures. The method, which applies a noninvasive medical imaging technique to a carbon nanotube-based sensor, is reported in the Journal of Nondestructive Evaluation., is documented in a paper published in the Journal of Nondestructive Evaluation in June.</description>
	<link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-07/uod-sta070716.php</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2016 00:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
	<guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-07/uod-sta070716.php</guid>
	
	
</item>
<item>
	<title>NASA sees Super Typhoon Nepartak approaching Taiwan</title>
	<description>(&lt;i&gt;NASA/Goddard Space Flight Center&lt;/i&gt;) As super typhoon Nepartak NASA satellites are gathering data on wind, temperature, rainfall, and cloud extent. NASA's Terra satellite, the Suomi NPP satellite and the RapidScat instrument have been analyzing the storm.</description>
	<link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-07/nsfc-nss070716.php</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2016 00:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
	<guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-07/nsfc-nss070716.php</guid>
	
	
</item>
<item>
	<title>NASA sees Tropical Depression 4E form</title>
	<description>(&lt;i&gt;NASA/Goddard Space Flight Center&lt;/i&gt;) The Suomi NPP satellite captured an image of newly formed Tropical Depression 4E in the Eastern Pacific Ocean.</description>
	<link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-07/nsfc-nst070716.php</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2016 00:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
	<guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-07/nsfc-nst070716.php</guid>
	
	
</item>
<item>
	<title>NASA peers into major Hurricane Blas</title>
	<description>(&lt;i&gt;NASA/Goddard Space Flight Center&lt;/i&gt;) As NASA satellites gather data on the first major hurricane of the Eastern Pacific Ocean hurricane season, Blas continues to hold onto its Category 3 status on the Saffir Simpson Wind Scale.</description>
	<link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-07/nsfc-npi070716.php</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2016 00:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
	<guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-07/nsfc-npi070716.php</guid>
	
	
</item>
<item>
	<title>Are narcissists addicted to social networking?</title>
	<description>(&lt;i&gt;Mary Ann Liebert, Inc./Genetic Engineering News&lt;/i&gt;) Social networking sites such as Facebook provide the ideal environment for some types of narcissists to promote themselves and seek the admiration of others on a grand scale, according to a study published in Cyberpsychology, Behavior, and Social Networking, a peer-reviewed journal from Mary Ann Liebert, Inc., publishers. The article is available free on the Cyberpsychology, Behavior, and Social Networking.</description>
	<link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-07/mali-ana070716.php</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2016 00:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
	<guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-07/mali-ana070716.php</guid>
	
	
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
